

Nikita Buevich

Product manager



Profile

Experienced and reliable product manager with a good sense of design and full of creative ideas. I combine skills of product and business management and technical background of front-end development.

I'm happy to work with smart, open-minded people and to use modern technologies and methodologies. I like to propose and implement hypotheses, influence the development of a project, design a product, plan development paths, experiment, implement new opportunities, argue about new functions, come up with ways out of hopeless business situations, analyze.

Employment History

Product owner at LPR

December 2019 — Present

Product manager at Trading View

October 2018 - May 2019 (8 months)

In TradingView I worked as product manager, but also combined functions of project manager.

- Established key road-map themes. Determined which features to add to the road-map
- · Led product team meetings, scrum meetings
- · Managed backlogs and prioritized technical work
- Wrote user stories and defined requirements for design and engineering teams. Produced feature specifications. Drafted release notes for product launches
- Collaborated with design, engineering and marketing teams
- · Monitored and optimized release cycle processes
- Worked with internal teams and stakeholders to generate ideas. Identified ideas that aligned with strategy. Explained why certain ideas were prioritized and others were not
- · Analyzed product feedback and requests

Contacts

+7 909 421 6222 / Russia nikitabuevich@gmail.com @nbuevich / Telegram

Date / place of birth 15.11.1992 Russia, Rostov-on-Don

Links

Personal website Facebook Twitter

Skills

Product management Agile Project Management Knowledgeable in UI/UX Web Development

Hobbies / Interests

Travelling. Investment and trading. Politics. Black and white film photography. MTB, climbing, snowboard, wakeboard, surf. Arthouse movies, smart books. Listening jazz. Drinking good wine and tea, eating tasty food.

Languages

Russian / Native English / Upper-intermediate

Product manager / Frontend architect at <u>GraphGrail</u> (MySmartChat)

January 2018 – August 2018 (8 months)

I came to MySmartChat (child project of GraphGrail) as contractor to help to choose suitable technologies, develop architecture of front-end and to make MVP. But the idea of project fascinated me and I stayed in it until the end.

After the core of prototype and UI-kit were developed, I counseled our HRs in front-end developers recruitment, interviewed. Then I mentored junior developers, realized code-review, controlled code-style and code quality.

I have taken part in a product launch as product manager. The main part of my job was behavior analysis of early adopters. I conducted user interviews, collected and analyzed feedback. Wrote user stories, defined requirements for engineering team, generated and tested ideas, based on collected data.

Also, important thing was customer on-boarding, delivering product demos for new features — I captured short videos of functionality usage, described features and trained our support team and first users.

Besides this, I helped to search for investors and took part in negotiations.

In addition, we had no designer in team, so I made design prototypes too.

Frontend consultant at AvtoTO

October 2016 – January 2018 (1 year 3 months)

I worked in AvtoTO as remote front-end consultant. The task was to make a redesign of the online store.

Developed scope assessment, established key road-map themes. Staff recruitment counseling (designer, front-end developers) and interviewing. Supervised UI/UX design development. Helped to choose technologies, developed architecture of front-end and UI-kit. Mentored front-end developers, realized code-review, code-style and code quality control. Set up business processes.

Web developer at Vezet Vsem

April 2015 - August 2017 (2 years 4 months)

Worked as front-end developer, using such technologies as JS, React+flux, ES6, webpack, HTML, SCSS, BEM, jQuery. Closely collaborated with design team.

Also took part in generating and explanation of priority of ideas, analyzed product feedback and requests, was interested in business case justification.

When I got more experience, started to mentor junior developers and make code review.

CTO at Saga Voyages

February 2015 — Present

Project manager at Plan B

September 2014 – January 2015 (1 year 4 months)

I worked as a partner with Plan B studio. I was responsible for the support of existing clients.

- Established key road-map themes. Determined which features to add to the road-map
- · Managed backlogs and prioritized technical work
- · Monitored and optimized release cycle processes
- Wrote user stories and defined requirements for design and engineering teams. Produced feature specifications. Draed release notes for product launches
- Worked with internal teams and stakeholders to generate ideas.
 Identified ideas that aligned with strategy. Explained why certain ideas were prioritized and others were not
- · Analyzed product feedback and requests
- · Negotiated with clients
- · Searched for contractors

CPO at 100% Sports

November 2012 - November 2013 (1 year)

I worked in a sport/extreme stuff shop "100% Sports". I was a head of the online store of this company and was responsible for the quality of service and for business metrics. I had a team of 5-10 managers and other staff. During 1 year of my work the project's revenue increased 4 times.

Own Projects

Owner at 357gramm (online tea-store)

July 2020 — Present

Soulmate at Edinstvo Gor (active recreation club)

September 2018 — Present

Co-owner Katuha (active recreation club)

October 2017 - May 2018 (8 months)

A small travel company that organizes holidays in the mountains (ski/snowboard, MTB, rafting, etc).

- Business strategy development; development and formalization of business processes; financial planning
- Marketing, SMM
- Team management (marketers, content-managers, tourism instructors, managers)
- Tours organization (negotiation with hotels, transport companies, tourism instructors, etc)

Co-owner / CTO at "Dvigaidelo" (web-studio)

February 2014 – April 2015 (1 year 2 months)

Together with a partner marketer we organized the small web studio. I was responsible for all aspects of business, connected with product development. During the year we have successfully implemented about 10 projects.

It was our first experience in business. Project has died because of financial problems (crisis of 2014) and our marketing mistake that we made a big bet on word mouth.

Education

Bachelor Degree in Applied Math and Computer Science at <u>Southern Federal University</u>, Rostov-on-Don

September 2009 - June 2013

Assistant translator in Math and Computer Science at Southern Federal University, Rostov-on-Don

September 2011 - May 2013



GoPractice, Data-driven growth and product management online training

In progress

Product Mindset, Program for the development of product thinking

February 2019 – April 2019

Academic art course at Art studio "Kolorit"

September 2005 – May 2009

References

References available upon request